Michael Buonomo

8 North Parkview Terrace Hazlet, New Jersey 07730

Cell: 732-513-7135 Email: <u>mike@buonomo.net</u>

Website: www.mikebuonomo.me

Summary

Web developer with experience building, implementing, and maintaining a large network of websites in a corporate setting, and an ambition to learn and build applications from new ideas. Well rounded with an understanding of front-end and back-end development, relational and nonrelational databases, and version control.

Experience

CareerCo

Software Engineer

Staten Island, New York September 2014 – Present

- Build, implement, and maintain new features for our large network of websites
- Developed and maintain a back-end admin which allows detailed customization and rapid deployment of new configurations for each of our website's result pages
- Built and maintain our E3 website which allows clients to access their candidate information, generate and download reports, invoices, and more
- Write and maintain a large number of scripts which allows integration with third party RESTful web services and APIs in order to send candidate information to clients in real time and batches
- Responsible for maintaining scripts to integrate with client TCPA compliance teams
- Agile development with 2-3 week sprints and daily scrums

Royal Communications Consultants

Junior Datacenter Technician (Intern)

New York, New York May 2013 – December 2013

• Installed/decommissioned servers and network devices

Education

William Paterson University of New Jersey

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Wayne, New Jersey Graduated May 2014

- Only student invited to the annual Computer Science Advisory Board Meeting in 2014 to present my Raspberry Pi LAMP server project which hosted my website
- Built a realtor website <u>www.keyhomesolutions.net</u>
- Developed a binary, hex, and decimal calculator app for Android

Technical Skills

Languages

- Proficient with PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3
- College background with C++, familiar with Java
- Exposure to Python, Ruby, Node

Frameworks and Infrastructure

- Zend Framework, jQuery, Bootstrap, Smarty Template Engine
- SVN, Git, Bash, Apache HTTP Server
- Windows, Mac, Linux, Microsoft Office, Jira

Qualifications

- Ability to learn new programming languages in a quick, effective manner
- Analytical and an effective troubleshooter
- Understanding of Agile Methodologies
- Ability to work on multiple projects simultaneously
- Organized and detail oriented
- Reliable and enthusiastic to learn

Other Projects

- Building a simple PHP MVC framework
- Configured a home web server used to host my websites, media files for streaming, and to learn
- Built a jokes website using Zend Framework 2 www.sendmejokes.com
- Used a Raspberry Pi webcam to monitor my front door over the internet